

PROFILE

About 4 years of experience in UI development / front-end development, development of rich user interface for professional web applications.

A capable, confident and multifaceted young professional with outstanding communication skills. Competent, hardworking, resourceful and a tactical planner, always enthusiastic to learn and undertake new challenges.

After a period of absence, focusing on the role as a mother of two, re-joined the workforce to become a proficient Javascript developer. Now, seeking to further hone skills in an organization of repute.

CONTACT

PHONE: 9962151965

WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/naomilemuel-509967120/

EMAIL:

naomichristabel 91@gmail.com

LANGUAGES

Fluent

English, Tamil

Basic

French, Hindi

NAOMI LEMUEL

FRONT-FND REACT IS DEVELOPER

SKILLS

Languages:

Javascript, Typescript, GraphQL, HTML5, CSS, Java, C, C++, MATLAB, IDL, Python

Frameworks:

React JS, Node JS, Express JS

Database:

MongoDB

Testing Frameworks:

React Testing Library, Jest, Enzyme

GIS & Digital Image Processing software:

QGIS, ArcGIS, Erdas IMAGINE, ENVI

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineer at Altimetrik India Pvt. Ltd. (PayPal Account)

April 2021 to present

Developed a **Single Page Web Application** from scratch, for *PayPal's Terminal Management System*. Built **reusable React components** along with **React Router**, implementing **Context API**. Used **React Testing Library**, **Jest** and **Enzyme** for mocking functions, writing unit tests along with **Istanbul** for coverage reports for the tested components.

Break in career

June 2018 to March 2021

Application Developer at IBM India Pvt. Ltd.

Aug 2013 to March 2016

Developed and maintained IBM proprietary intranet wiki and web pages, using **Javascript**, **HTML & CSS**, being part of the web content management team

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

May 2022

Developed a **full stack web application** (for clinic consultation appointment booking) using the **MERN stack**, integrated **payment gateway** and **deployed to Heroku**.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Collaborated research project with the Institute of Remote Sensing, Anna University and Sri Ramachandra Institute of Higher Education & Research (Masters' thesis)

Dec 2017 to May 2018

Developed an **Android application** for assessing Urban Heat Island (UHI) and automated the disaggregation algorithm by developing an **IDL widget application**

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: **27-12-1991**

GENDER: **Female**

FATHER'S NAME: **Dr. WMS Johnson**

NATIONALITY: Indian

HOBBIES

Writina

Personal blog: Incessant Intricacies

YouTube Content Creation

Tutoring vocabulary and grammar: French, English, Hindi

Keyboard

Intermediate level graded examination in Music Performance, Trinity College, London Grade 5 – passed with merit, Oct 2006

Art

Worked with pencil sketches and painting in water and oil colours

Cooking

Ardent about trying out new recipes

Research Internship at IIT – Madras (Environmental and Water Resources Engineering Division)

May 2017 to June 2017

Estimated evapo-transpiration using energy balance model with satellite imagery in **MATLAB**

Collaborated research project with the Institute of Remote Sensing, Anna University and Central Institute for Brackish-water Aquaculture (Bachelors' thesis)

Jan 2013 to May 2013

Worked with the **ArcSWAT** module of **ArcGIS** to estimate surface runoff and sediment yield by SWAT Modelling of the Coleroon watershed

Short-term summer research internship with the Remote Sensing Working Group at the University of Kiel, Germany

May 2012 to July 2012

Designed and programmed **a tidal model in IDL programming** language, for the coast of Helgoland to assist image analysis

EDUCATION

M.E. Remote Sensing & Geomatics - Aug 2016 to May 2018 College of Engineering – Guindy, Anna University, Chennai **CGPA: 9.99 on 10**

B.E. Geo-informatics - Aug 2009 to May 2013 College of Engineering – Guindy, Anna University, Chennai **CGPA: 9.15 on 10**

Higher Secondary (Std. 12) - June 2008 to March 2009 CSI Jessie Moses Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai **Percentage marks: 97.75%**

Matriculation Board (Std. 10) - June 2006 to March 2007 CSI Jessie Moses Matriculation Higher Secondary School, Chennai Percentage marks: 93.7%

TRAININGS ATTENDED

React JS, Node JS, GraphQL - Self-learning (April 2021till present)

Programming in Python - Self-learning (Feb 2021 till March 2021)

Programming in Java - As part of onboarding at IBM (June to Aug 2013)

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Gold medalist and 1st Rank holder in Anna University – M.E. Remote Sensing and Geomatics (May 2018)

Awarded the 'Adarsh Naren Chintala Endowment Award' for 'BEST STUDENT – Masters' Course in Image Processing – (2017-18)

Awarded the 'Geomatic Endowment Award' (2017-18)

Awarded a DAAD-WISE Scholarship (Deutscher Akademischer Austausch Dienst / German Academic Exchange Service – Working Internships in Science and Engineering) (May 2012)

Ranked 1st in school and 1st among all the Chennai Diocese Schools, Higher Secondary Board Examination (March 2009)